

# Saugat Maharjan

UI/UX & Graphic Designer

🔀 saugatmaharjan11@gmail.com



**J** +977-9843687180



• Dhalko-17, Kathmandu

#### **Profile**

I am an UI/UX Designer from Kathmandu, Nepal who loves graphic designing with IT engineering degree, I create product from the user research to the high-fidelity design with 1 year of experience. I am highly flexible and adaptable when it comes to different projects and freelance work. My interest in design field sparked during pursuing the degree.

Besides technology, I love travelling, drawing, playing video games, listening to music, learn new things and face exciting challenges and I am a FOODIE.

# **Employment**

**Design Intern** 

Dec 2021 - Apr 2022

IntroCept, Kumaripati, Lalitpur

**Associate UI/UX & Graphic Designer** 

May 2022 - Present

IntroCept, Kumaripati, Lalitpur

#### Education

#### **School Leaving Certificate**

2015

80.38% - First Division with Distinction

Maha Manjushree H.S School, Sitapaila, Kathamndu

#### **Higher Secondary Education**

2015 - 2017

65.90% - First Division

Kathmandu Model College, Bagbazzar, Kathmandu

**Bachelor of Engineering in Information Technology** 2017 - 2021

**CGPA - 3.17** 

Nepal College of Information Technology, Balkumari, Lalitpur

#### Personal Details

Date of Birth

April 9, 1999

Place of Birth

Kathmandu, Nepal

Nationality

Nepali

Citizenship No.

27-01-72-02309

Gender

Male

Driver's License

03-06-00762856

Website

www.saugatmaharjan.com

.np

Linkedin

https://www.linkedin.com/in/

saugat-

maharjan-471a86225/

**Blood Group** 

O +ve

# Certificates

Foundations of User Experience (UX) Design	Jun 2022
Start the UX Design Process: Empathize, Define and Ideate	Jul 2022
Build Wireframes and Low-Fidelity Prototypes	Aug 2022
Conduct UX Research and Test Early Concepts	Sep 2022
Create High-Fidelity Designs and Prototypes in Figma	Oct 2022

#### Courses

Programming in C	2017
Object Oriented Programming in C++	2017
Web Technology	2018
Programming in Java	2018
Database Management System	2019
Software Engineering Fundamentals	2019
Object Oriented Design and Modeling through UML	2020
Organization and Management	2020
IP Switching and Routing (Elective I)	2021
Advanced Web Technology (Elective II)	2021

# Internships

**Design Intern** 

Dec 2021 - Apr 2022

Skills

Figma

Adobe XD

Illustrator

Webflow

Photoshop

HTML/CSS

#### Qualities

- Active Person, Problem-Solving, Presevering, Reliable, Flexible.
- Compatible and Friendly, Teamwork and Collaborations.
- Analytical Thinking.
- Strong ability to balance multiple priorities with excellent time management skills.
- Ability to lead and work well in teams.
- Planning Research Projects.
- Excellent oral and written communication and presentation skills, ability to communicate confidently.

IntroCept, Kumaripati, Lalitpur

# **Academic Projects**

Library Management System using Python and Django

2019

First Project (4th semester)

**Smart Travel Planning Application** using Flutter with Dart

2020

Minor Project (6th semester)

Ghumfir : Companion Finder as an UI/UX Designer

2021

Major Project (8th semester)

Ghumfir-Figma

# Professional Projects

Flower Catalogue App

2022

Flower Catalogue App for Trendy Florist - Figma

Ghumfir

2022

Ghumfir-Figma

**Employee Task Management** 

2022

Employee Task Management - Figma

Blog Site

2022

Blogpost Article - Figma

Cab Booking

2022

Cab Booking - Figma

# Extracurricular Activities

First position in Inter-house Football

Feb 2014

Annual sports week held by school.

**Second Position on Men's Cricket** 

Feb 2020

Held on occassion od Annual Sports Day by NCIT college.

#### Languages

Nepali

English

Newari

Hindi

# **Achievements**

- Awarded by Kilagha Twa: for securing Distinction position among SLC candidates on 5th December 2015.
- Received Scholarship to study Intermediate (+2 Science) program for securing good marks in entrance exam at Kathmandu Model College.
- Received cash prize for being topper in IT department in NCIT college in 5th semester.

#### Social Medias

Facebook - Saugat Maharjan | Facebook

Instagram - (@s.a\_u.g.a.t\_7)

Linkedin - Saugat Maharjan | LinkedIn

#### **Declaration**

I consent to the processing of my personal data for purpose of recruitment for the position to which I am applying. I hereby declare that all the mentioned particulars are true about myself and take all the responsibilities for their correctness.

#### **Hobbies**

- Travelling
- Drawing
- Video Games
- Football, Futsal
- Music, Movies
- Exploring and Learning History